# Chi (Violet) Zhang



violet1004zc@gmail.com



+64 02108976758



in linkedin.com/in/chi-zhang-7b16b9284



https://violetzzzzzz.github.io/myweb/

#### **SUMMARY**

I'm currently a student in the Master of Software Development at Victoria University of Wellington, with an expected graduation date in June 2024.

Throughout my academic journey, I have gained proficiency in various programming languages such as Java, PHP, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Through practical experiences, I expanded my skill set with JavaFX, C#, Python, React, TypeScript, and MySQL through diverse projects.

I'm excited about the prospect of applying these technical skills, combined with my communication and negotiation skills developed through working in early childhood education, to a future role in the IT industry.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Logical Thinking and Scientific Mindset
- Extensive lab time during my undergraduate studies honed my laboratory techniques, analysis skills, and academic precision.
- General Programming Skills and Thinking
- I've honed strong logical thinking and programming skills through coursework and hands-on projects in my current program.
- Proficiency in Java, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React, along with essential skills in Python and C#, supported by practical experience.
- As Java is the primary content of my current program, I've done lots of practices in Java. I've also created projects using, Python, and C#, and gained valuable experience in web development with HTML, PHP, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, and React.

# **SOFT SKILLS**

- Effective Communication and Collaboration
- My prior teaching experience has honed my effective communication and collaboration skills, interacting with tamariki, kaiako and whanau.
- Problem Solving and Adaptability
- I excel in problem-solving, seamlessly adapting from research to teaching and software development. This journey, marked by extensive self-learning, highlights my proactive approach to problem-solving and adaptability.

# PROJECT EXPERIENCE (ACADEMIC)

- A Canvas Module: a real-time, interactive whiteboard-style interface (Industry Group Project)
- React, TypeScript, JavaScript, C#
- I contributed to the development of a 2D animated sprite that moves with the cursor on the canvas, allowing real-time position sharing with other users working on the same canvas.

# • A Stock Management System (Group Project)

- Java, JavaFX, CSS
- I contributed to the development, specifically working on the implementation of saving and loading data as well as rendering the stock table on the dashboard.

# • Secure Text Document Encryption and Decryption Software

- Java, JavaFX, AWS RDS MySQL
- A project that allows users to type text or upload files for encryption or decryption. It also has authentication feature and uses AWS RDS to store data.

#### Contact List

- Version 1: .NET MAUI, C#, MySQL. Version 2: Python, Tkinter, MySQL
- A contact list that allows users to manage contacts, and it has authentication feature and uses AWS RDS MySQL to store data.

### • My Online Portfolio

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React
- An Online Image Gallery
- HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, MySQL
- An online image gallery that allows user to create their albums and add photos.

#### **EDUCATION**

### Master of Software Development

- 07/2023 6/2024 (expected graduation date)
- Grade: Prof Programming Skills A+, Software Development Studio 1 A

Victoria University of Wellington, New Zealand

# Graduate Diploma of Early Childhood Teaching

- 05/2019 - 05/2020

New Zealand Tertiary College, Auckland, New Zealand

#### **Bachelor of Pharmacy**

- 09/2014 - 06/2018

Sichuan University, Sichuan, China

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Registered Early Childhood Teacher

- 08/2020 - 07/2023

Educare Tawa, Tawa, Wellington

# Reliever Early Childhood Teacher

**- 07/2019 - 07/2020** 

Beststart, Meadowbank, Auckland

#### PERSONAL INTERESTS

Painting, Crafts, Jazz&K-pop dance, Snorkelling, Steam and Board Game.

References available upon request